Hello, my friends.
And welcome to exercise number 16.
And this exercise, we are going to find the complexity of this function.
All set.
OK.
So this function often contains a loop if all loop and this loop will print out I and the Fibonacci
so fib I, it will go and call the method and this method we have seen in the previous video.
So both the video and think about solving this exercise and getting the correct time complexity of it.
Please note, ever what you what you solve, what you will gain, but you will understand that.
So as you more practice, as the more you become a master in data structure and algorithms and even
all coding related topics.
OK, so let's begin if we start with avoid all fib, we have a loop and here the loop, as I told you
and as we have solved before, when you see a loop, look at the the initial condition, the stopping
condition and the weight of increment, the way of increment + plus.
This means that all that we are going to go through all the elements from zero to N.
So we are going to execute this statement and time.
So from zero to end and the weight of increment plus plus.
So it is all of an OK, but we are calling a function and calling a function depends on.
The function algorithm, the function complexity itself.
OK, so we need to calculate the function time complexity in order to get the correct time complexity
of this algorithm.
When you see Fibonacci.
But in mind that we have an exponential.
OK, so we have solved this before.
And we said that Fibonacci F and minus one and my Fibonacci and minus two.
This would result in zero of two.
Please go back to exercise number 15.
To better understand this function.
OK.
But the trick here in this question, it is not just calling the function.
We are inside the elu calling every time this function.
So here we have and times, so we are going to call the function and times and the function complexity
is to end.
Therefore, the complexity of this is n times due to power.
And remember, guys, you are not asked to get a common complexity, a very simple complexity like two
and factorial and square.
You are asked in in the interview order the exam in university to solve complex things and compound
complexities.
OK, so enzymes two to power and is the solution of this exercise because Fibonacci will act as do it
to power and.
And we have seen it in the exercise number 15.
OK.
We took an example.
Let me show you if we took an example, it was an equal to five.
OK.
And equal to five, all FIB will execute at the five.
It will loop through five times from zero to five, OK, and recall the function fib.
And then pass five.
OK.
We have seen five in the previous video.
It is equal to one at two five.
Sorry.
OK, so Fibonacci of five is equal to.
The Fibonacci.
Of five is equal to five.
This would result in five.
OK.
And we are going to execute I so zero.
One, two, three, four and two four, so Ford will be giving.
As for us as five.
OK, so the fourth element in Fibonacci.
Of The Fifth Element would be five, so five for Wenatchee is equal to five.
OK.
Therefore, since we are depending on the end here, the end of the loop and the and in the Fibonacci,
we have to enforce Fibonacci and end for the loop.
Multiplying them by together would result and times to the power.